SHAYAN KAZEMI TEHRANI

Machine Learning Software Engineer

@ shayanthrn@gmail.com

(+1) 438-979-6137

Montreal, Canada

% shayanthrn.github.io

in shayan-tehrani

shayanthrn

SUMMARY

As an experienced professional with over 4 years of experience as a Senior Software Engineer, I have successfully designed and developed a doctors' appointment booking system and played a key role in designing and developing the IDmelon SSO system. My expertise lies in Distributed and Cloud-Based Software Engineering and Machine Learning reflecting my commitment to delivering innovative solutions in the fields.

EXPERIENCE

Web Chair

The Canadian Society of Information Theory

£ 2023

Montreal, Canada

Design, Development and Deployment of the 31st Biennial Symposium on Communications 2023 (BSC 2023) conference.

Software Engineer

IDmelon Technologies Inc.

2022-2023

♥ Vancouver, Canada

- Design and develop a robust SSO server for IDmelon and host it on Google Cloud with more than 500 active
 users.
- Played a key role in enhancing the software architecture, ensuring scalability and maintainability for the IDmelon SSO system.
- Utilized React for frontend development, improving the user interface and overall user experience.
- Contributed to CI/CD pipelines to streamline the development and deployment processes.
- Collaborated in Scrum teams for streamlined project management
- Implemented microservices architecture to create a flexible and modular system.
- Designed, developed, and maintained RESTful APIs, connecting the SSO server with 10+ applications and services.
- Utilized Docker for containerization to simplify deployment and scaling of the application.

Senior Software Engineer

Vira Co.

2019-2021

▼ Tehran, Iran

- Integrated messaging and payment APIs to optimize system functionality and payment processing.
- Managed server operations, optimizing performance, reliability, and availability to meet project requirements.
- Released project source code on GitHub, fostering community collaboration and transparency.

PROJECTS

Food Intake Monitoring System

django, python, kotlin, pytorch, numpy, computer vision

• Developed an Android application for food intake monitoring, employing advanced computer vision techniques.

Webfolio

javascript, python, django, linkedin api, chatgpt api, ,html5, css, bootstrap, jquery

- Designed and developed an intelligent portfolio website creation system that leverages data-driven recommendations.
- Integrated technologies such as LinkedIn API, ChatGPT API.

Any-to-Many Voice Conversion Application

audio processing, deep learning, gan, ltsm, mongodb, express, node, socket.io

- Developed an innovative Voice Conversion Application as the focus of my BS thesis, utilizing advanced machine learning models.
- Employed a robust technology stack and audio processing techniques to create a comprehensive voice conversion solution.

NeuroEvolutionGamer

genetic algorithm, deep learning, pygame

 Al agent learning to play mini game (something like floppy bird) using neural network and genetic algorithm to train neural network

UbuntuOS Portfolio

javascript, nextjs, tailwindcss

• Created a distinctive personal portfolio website with an Ubuntu 20.04 theme.

GCMC, Movie Recommendation System

pytorch, numpy, dgl

 Implemented GCMC(Graph Convolution Matrix Completion) by DGL(DEEP GRAPH LIBRARY) to recommend movies based on user ratings

EDUCATION

MASc. Computer Engineering

Concordia University

2022-Present

BSc. Computer Engineering

Amirkabir University of Technology (Tehran Polytechnic)

2017-2022

SKILLS



LANGUAGES